A Finding Aid to the Jackson Pollock and Lee Krasner Papers, circa 1914-1984, bulk 1942-1984, in the Archives of American Art AAA.polljack
Archives of American Art
- Jackson Pollock papers and Lee Krasner papers about Jackson Pollock, circa 1914-1984; Series 1; (Box 1-7, 16, OV 18; 7.0 linear feet)
  - Writings by Others, 1950-circa 1983, undated; 1.3
    - Bryan Robertson, Jackson Pollock, draft copy, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Alvin Schwartz, Untitled Essay, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Eugene Victor Thaw, Untitled Essay, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Parker Tyler, "Jackson Pollock: The Infinite Labyrinth,", 1950 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Unidentified Author, "Jackson Pollock,", 1957 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - James Valliere Research Material on Jackson Pollock, 1963-1972; 1.4
    James Valliere was a graduate student at the University of New Hampshire who was employed in 1963 by Lee Krasner to begin researching Pollock's early career and compile a general catalog of his work. Valliere never published the results of his research and the materials were kept by Lee Krasner. Found here is correspondence between Valliere and Lee Krasner, as well as Valliere's research correspondence with other family members, and Pollock's friends and colleagues. There is correspondence with Mr. and Mrs. Charles Pollock, Sanford McCoy (Pollock's brother), Jay Pollock, Thomas Hart Benton, Robert Motherwell, and the Art Students League of New York. Also found are transcripts and audio recordings of interviews conducted by Valliere with those who knew Pollock well, including James Brooks, Reuben Kadish, Tony Smith, Clement Greenberg, and Pollock's sister-in-law Mrs. Sanford (Arloie) McCoy wherein she reads several letters Jackson wrote to his father from New York. Also included in this series are some of Valliere's research notes and photographs of James Brooks, and Pollock's friend Daniel Miller taken during their interviews. Untranscribed audio recordings of interviews are filed in series 1.10: Audio and Video Recordings and Film.
    All of the sound recordings in this series have been digitized for research access.
    - Correspondence, 1963-1967; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 53-55)
    - Notes, 1963-1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Photographs of James Brooks, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Photographs of Daniel T. Miller, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Preliminary Catalog of Jackson Pollock's Library, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - James Brooks Interview, 1965; 1 sound tape reels Duplicate; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript Original (Box 2, Folder 60-62)
    - Clement Greenberg Interview Transcript, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Clement Greenberg Interview, 1968; 2 sound tape reels Original (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Reuben Kadish Interview, Transcript, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mrs. Sanford McCoy Interview, 1965; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript Original (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Daniel T. Miller Interview, 1965; 1 sound tape reels Duplicate; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript Original (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
    - Tony Smith Interview, Transcript, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Interview with Lee Krasner, Mr. and Mrs. Charles Maddox, Dorothy Dehner, and Robert Miller, Transcript, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Essay, "Jackson Pollock's Progressed Lunation Cycle,", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Business Records, circa 1942-1983; 1.5
    Business records document Lee Krasner's handling of Pollock's estate and exhibition of his artwork after his death. Found here are miscellaneous business records, including price lists, lists of items loaned for exhibitions, warehouse and shipping receipts, conservation receipts, and other handwritten notes. There are lists of owners of paintings and exhibitions, a guest book from the Venice "Biennale, and a complete appraisal of 37 Jackson Pollock drawings. There is also a folder of account statements and inventory lists from the Marlborough Gallery. Legal Documents include a deposition by Francis O'Connor regarding his interviews with Pollock's therapist, Dr. Joseph Henderson.
    - Miscellaneous Business Records, 1957-1983, undated; (2 folders; partially scanned) (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
    - List of Owners of Paintings, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Exhibition Lists, 1942-1959 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Guest Book, Venice "Biennale,", 1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Marlborough Gallery Account with the Pollock Estate, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Legal Documents, Francis O'Connor Deposition, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Appraisal of Jackson Pollock Drawings, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Printed Material, 1942-1983; 1.6
    Printed materials include books and book proofs, such as a small book in Italian critiquing Pollock's work and proofs for two biographies by Frank O'Hara and Bryan Robertson, magazines with feature articles on Pollock, and numerous newspaper and magazine clippings spanning forty years. Also found are exhibition catalogs, posters, press releases, announcements, and invitations for both Pollock's solo and group exhibitions.
    - Book, Masterpieces of the World (in Japanese), undated; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Book, Museum of Modern Art New York in Bern (in German), 1978; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Book, Pollock: un saggio critico di Enrico Crispolti, 1958; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Book Proof, Betty Parsons Gallery Catalog, 1951; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Book Proof, Edwin Miller, for the essay "The Radical Vision of Whitman and Pollock,", 1970; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Book Proof, Museum of Modern Art Jackson Pollock Exhibition Catalog, 1967; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Book Proof, Frank O'Hara, Jackson Pollock, 1959; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Book Proof, Bryan Robertson, Jackson Pollock, 1959-1960; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Book Proofs, unidentified, circa 1964; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Clippings, 1943-1951, undated; (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 29-34)
    - Clippings, 1952-1960; (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
    - Clippings, 1961-1970; (6 folders; Oversized items in Box 16, F1) (Box 4, Folder 8-13)
    - Clippings, 1971-1983; (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 14-19)
    - Clippings, Beaubourg Exhibition, 1982; (3 folders; in french) (Box 4, Folder 20-22)
    - Clippings, Reviews of Jackson Pollock by Bryan Robertson, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Clippings, Reviews of Jackson Pollock: Energy Made Visible by B. H. Friedman, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1944-1964, 1974-1983, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Solo Exhibitions, 1943-1979; (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 27-31)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Group Exhibitions, 1942-1949 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Group Exhibitions, 1950-1970; (14 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-14)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Group Exhibitions, 1971-1977; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Exhibition Posters, 1950-1980; (Oversized items in OV 18) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Magazines, LIFE, 1949, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Magazines, Miscellaneous, 1958, 1963, 1967, 1976-1977; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Press Releases for Pollock Exhibitions, 1976-1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1974-1983, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1967; (Scanned with Box 4, F8-13) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 1)
    - Exhibition Posters, 1950-1980; (See also Box 6, F3; not scanned) (Box OV 18)
  - Scrapbooks, 1943-1957; 1.7
    Two scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings, magazine clippings, and exhibition announcements. One was created by Pollock and Krasner, and the other was created by Krasner in the years following Pollock's death.
    - Scrapbook, 1943-1949 (Box 16 (sol), Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook kept by Lee Krasner, 1956-1957 (Box 16 (sol), Folder 3)
  - Artwork by Others, undated; 1.8
    Found here is one sketchbook containing primarily ink drawings and diagrams by an unidentified artist.
    - Sketchbook by Unidentified Artist, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, circa 1914-1969; 1.9
    Found here are extensive photographs of Pollock. There are many photographs of Pollock as a child and teenager and with his family, of Pollock with Lee Krasner in the studio, outdoors, at their home on Long Island, and with family and friends, including photographs from a 1950 Pollock family reunion held at their home. Also found are exhibition photographs, including his 1951 solo exhibition at Betty Parsons Gallery, as well as photos of Pollock's studio, and a few other miscellaneous images. Several of the photographs of Pollock in his studio were taken by Wilfrid Zogbaum, Hans Namuth, and Rudy Burckhardt. Significant figures photographed with Pollock include Clement Greenberg, Helen Frankenthaler, James Brooks, and David Alfaro Siqueiros. There are also numerous photographs and slides of Pollock's works of art that have not been scanned. Photographs are arranged according to subject and chronologically within each folder.
    - Portraits of Jackson Pollock, 1943-circa 1955, undated; (Oversized items in Box 16, F4) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Portraits of Jackson Pollock by Hans Namuth, 1950; (Oversized items in Box 16, F5) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Portraits of Jackson Pollock, Copy Prints and Negatives, 1943-circa 1955; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Jackson Pollock in His Studio by Wilfrid Zogbaum, circa 1947; (Oversized items in Box 16, F6) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Jackson Pollock in His Studio by Rudy Burckhardt, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Jackson Pollock in His Studio by Hans Namuth, 1950; (Oversized items in Box 16, F7) (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Jackson Pollock in His Studio, Copy Prints and Negatives, circa 1947, 1950; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Jackson Pollock and Family, circa 1914-1930, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Jackson Pollock and Family, Copy Prints and Negatives, circa 1914-1930, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Jackson Pollock and Lee Krasner, circa 1946-1955; (2 folders; Oversized items in Box 16, F8) (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
    - Jackson Pollock and Lee Krasner, Copy Prints and Negatives, circa 1946-1955; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Pollock and Krasner with Friends and Family, 1936-1956; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
    - Pollock and Krasner with Friends and Family, Copy Prints and Negatives, 1936-1956; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Pollock Family Reunion, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Pollock Family Reunion, Copy Prints and Negatives, 1950; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Pollock-Krasner Studio by Maurice Berezov, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Exhibition, Betty Parsons Gallery, 1951; (Oversized items in Box 16, F9-11) (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Exhibition, Betty Parsons Gallery, Copy Prints and Negatives, 1951; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Exhibition, Bennington College, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Exhibitions, Sidney Janis Gallery, 1952-1958 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Exhibitions, Unidentified, 1958, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Exhibition, Kunstverein fur die Rheinlande und Westfalen, 1961; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
    - Exhibition, Moderna Museet, circa 1963 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Exhibitions, Marlborough Gallery of Art, 1964, 1969, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
    - Exhibitions, Museum of Modern Art, 1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1942-1948, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, Copy Prints and Negatives, 1942-1948, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Artwork, 1969, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Slides of Artwork, 1950, undated; (not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Color Transparencies of Pollock Artwork Owned by Lee Krasner, undated; (not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Stereo Transparencies of Pollock-Krasner Studio, undated; (not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Safety Negatives, undated; (not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Portraits of Jackson Pollock, 1943-circa 1955, undated; (Scanned with Box 6, F10) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 4)
    - Portraits of Jackson Pollock by Hans Namuth, 1950; (Scanned with Box 6, F11) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 5)
    - Jackson Pollock in His Studio by Wilfrid Zogbaum, circa 1947; (Scanned with Box 6, F14) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 6)
    - Jackson Pollock in His Studio by Hans Namuth, 1950; (Scanned with Box 6, F16) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 7)
    - Jackson Pollock and Lee Krasner, circa 1946-1955; (2 folders; Scanned with Box 6, F20-21) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 8)
    - Exhibition, Betty Parsons Gallery, 1951; (Scanned with Box 6, F29) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 9-11)
  - Audio and Video Recordings and Film, 1964, 1966; 1.10
    This subseries contains a 16 mm film about Pollock, entitled, "Jackson Pollock: A Reconsideration," including a reel of outtakes, produced in 1964 by Channel 13 WNDT, the Educational Broadcasting Corporation. There are also VHS copies of the film. Also found are untranscribed audio recordings of interviews conducted by James Valliere while he was researching Pollock's early career and artwork for a never-published book on Pollock. Interviews are with artists Willem De Kooning and Alfonso Ossorio, and Pollock's friends Burton Rouche. Researchers should also see Series 1.4: James Valliere Research Material on Jackson Pollock for additional recordings of interviews with transcripts.
    All of the sound recordings in this series have been digitized for research access. Video access copies of the films are also available.
    - "Jackson Pollock: A Reconsideration,", 1964; 1 Film reels 16 mm (Box Motion Picture Film)
    - "Jackson Pollock: A Reconsideration," Outtakes, 1964; 3 Film reels 16 mm; 1 Film reels 35 mm (Box Motion Picture Film)
    - "Jackson Pollock: A Reconsideration", 1964; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Video is access copy for motion picture film.
    - "Jackson Pollock: A Reconsideration," Outtakes, 1964; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Willem De Kooning interview with James Valliere, 1966; 1 sound tape reels (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Alfonso Ossorio interview with James Valliere, 1966; 2 Sound cassettes Duplicates; 1 sound tape reels Duplicate; 1 sound tape reels Original (Box 7, Folder 8-10)
    - Ruth and Tino Nivola interview with James Valliere, 1966; 1 sound tape reels (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Burton Rouche interview with James Valliere, 1966; 1 sound tape reels (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Lee Krasner Papers, circa 1927-1984; Series 2; (Box 7-15, 17; 8.6 linear feet)
  This series consists primarily of papers documenting Lee Krasner's artistic career and personal life during the last twenty years of her life. The bulk of the material dates from 1964 to 1984. Biographical material documents Krasner's family background, education, and career through chronologies, awards, resumes, exhibition lists, bibliographies, address books, and mementoes from Krasner's 1965 trip to England. Professional and personal correspondence is with gallery owners, curators, art historians and critics, students, fans, family, and fellows artists such as Cleve Gray, Alfonso Ossorio, and Philip Johnson.
  There are thirteen transcripts of interviews with Krasner conducted by art historians and journalists. The interviews discuss Krasner's life and career, the art scene in New York, and her relationship with Jackson Pollock. Original audio recordings exist for many of the interviews and are filed in 2.10, Audio and Video Recordings. Writings by others consist of draft essays about Krasner and her artwork; writings by Lee Krasner consist of handwritten lecture notes and notes containing reminiscences. Business and financial records consist of loan forms, sales lists, guest lists, exhibition checklists, and other miscellaneous materials. Krasner's papers also include one scrapbook of news clippings and photographs from her 1965 Whitechapel exhibition.
  Printed material consists of exhibition materials for Krasner's solo and group shows, event announcements, programs, numerous newspaper and magazine clippings, and faculty materials for her work at the Cooper Union. Numerous photographs include photographs of Krasner with Pollock, family, and friends, and photos of her home and studio. The majority of photographs are professional portraits of Krasner taken throughout her career, including portraits by Hans Namuth. Also found are photographs of Krasner at exhibitions, exhibition installations, and photographs of her artwork. Audio and video recordings include Krasner interviews, recorded radio and television shows, lectures, and a VHS recording of "Pollock a Beaubourg. Transcripts for many of the interviews are filed in Series 2.3.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned from microfilm. All of the sound recordings in this series have also been digitized for research access.
  The Lee Krasner Papers series is arranged into 10 subseries:
  2.1: Biographical Material, circa 1927-1983
  2.2: Correspondence, circa 1941-1984
  2.3: Interview Transcripts, circa 1965-1979
  2.4: Writings by Others, circa 1965-1981
  2.5: Writings by Lee Krasner, circa 1977-1979
  2.6: Business and Financial Records, circa 1957-1983
  2.7: Scrapbook, 1965
  2.8: Printed Material, circa 1942-1984
  2.9: Photographs, circa 1929-1983
  2.10: Audio and Video Recordings, circa 1964-1983
  The arrangement is based primarily on the original microfilm arrangement.
  - Biographical Material, circa 1927-1983; 2.1
    Found here are Lee Krasner's genealogical notes, school transcripts, certificate of marriage to Jackson Pollock, and Who's Who biographies. Also included are resumes and artist statements, chronologies, exhibition lists, bibliographies, and address books. Awards and certificates include an award medal for the Chevalier de l'Ordre des Arts et des Lettres. There are also mementos such as brochures, receipts, programs, and letters, from her 1965 visit to England for the Whitechapel Gallery exhibition.
    - Biographical Documents, 1927-1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Biographical Data and Chronologies, 1964-1983, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Exhibition Lists, 1965-1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Bibliographies, 1983, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Award Medals, 1977, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Award Ceremony Programs, 1977, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Award Certificates, 1972-1982; (Oversized items in Box 17, F1) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Address Books, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - "Personal Mementos from England Trip", 1965; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
    - Award Certificates, 1982; (Scanned with Box 9, F19) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, circa 1941-1984; 2.2
    Lee Krasner's correspondence spans over forty years, but the bulk of it ranges from 1970 to her death in 1984. Found here is correspondence with galleries and gallery owners that represented her, exhibited her work, or requested her work for potential exhibitions. Krasner was friends with many artists and art professionals and her personal correspondence includes many letters from artists such as Philip Johnson, Ray Eames, Cleve Gray, and Hans Namuth. She also corresponded with art historians and critics, curators, collectors, arts and social organizations, admirers, and family members. Additionally, this series includes fan mail, student inquiries, correspondence with journalists and publishers, requests for her to lecture, and business correspondence on the sale of her work. There are numerous letters and telegrams congratulating Krasner on exhibitions, such as the 1965 Whitechapel retrospective and extensive documentation of her 1958 commission to create a mural for Uris Brothers, Inc.
    See Index for List of Notable Correspondents from Series 2.2
    Letters are arranged chronologically and include both letters received by Krasner and handwritten or typed drafts sent by Krasner. Later in her life many of the drafts were written by her secretary.
    Index: List of Notable Correspondents from Series 2.2
    List represents only a selection of correspondents.
    Albright-Knox Art Gallery
    American Federation of Arts
    Appelhof, Ruth Ann
    Asher, Elise
    Australian National Gallery
    Barron, Maida
    Berkson, Bill
    Collier, Oscar
    Cooper Union
    County of Nassau Office of Cultural Development
    Diamonstein, Barbaralee
    Dickler, Gerald
    Eames, Ray
    Englesmith, Tejas
    Erskine, Halley
    Forge, Andrew (Yale University)
    Franklin Siden Gallery
    Friedman, B. H.
    Friedman, Sanford
    Glaser, Bruce
    Goodman, Naomi
    Gray, Cleve
    Gregory-Hood, Alex (Rowan Gallery)
    Guggenheim Museum
    Guild Hall
    Holladay, Billie
    Howard, Richard
    Howell, Douglas Morse
    Hubbard, E. W.
    Janie C. Lee Gallery
    Johnson, Philip
    Landau, Ellen
    Lauck, Anthony
    Lloyd, Frank
    Marlborogh Fine Art, Ltd.
    Martha Jackson Gallery
    Matter, Mercedes
    McHenry, Barnabas (Barney)
    Michael, Marjorie
    Museum of Modern Art
    Myers, John Bernard
    Namuth, Hans
    Nemser, Cindy
    New York WPA Artists, Inc.
    Nochlin, Linda
    Novak, Barbara
    O'Connor, Francis
    Oppler, Ellen
    Ossorio, Alfonso
    Pace Gallery
    Parrish Art Museum
    Pavia, Philip
    Pollock, Jay
    Rago, Louise Elliott
    Robert Miller Gallery
    Robertson, Bryan
    Rose, Barbara
    Russell, Bertrand
    Schilling, Marge
    School of Visual Arts
    Sidney Janis Gallery
    Siegel, Adele
    Smithsonian Institution
    Spaeth, Elaine
    Stasik, Andrew
    Still, Clyfford
    Stony Brook Foundation
    Tate Gallery
    Thaw, Eugene V.
    Thayer, Jeanne
    Valliere, James
    Van Fossen, Ted
    Whitechapel Art Gallery
    Whitney, David
    Whitney Museum of American Art
    Wise, Howard
    - Correspondence, undated; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1960; (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 3-6)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1965; (9 folders) (Box 8, Folder 7-15)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1970; (7 folders) (Box 8, Folder 16-22)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1976; (19 folders) (Box 8, Folder 23-41)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1980; (21 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-21)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1984; (20 folders) (Box 9, Folder 22-41)
  - Interview Transcripts, circa 1965-1979; 2.3
    This subseries contains transcripts of interviews of Lee Krasner conducted by various art historians and journalists. The interviews discuss Krasner's work, the early abstract expressionist movement, her relationship with Jackson Pollock, and the "New York art world". Two of the transcripts are for broadcast interviews, including a 1979 interview with Barbara Novak for WGBH New Television Workshop, Boston. Transcripts are arranged chronologically. Audio recordings for these interviews are filed in Series 2.10.
    - Bruce Glaser Interview, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Barbara Cavaliere Interview, undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous Interviews, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Andrew Forge Interview, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Emily Wasserman Interview, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Barbara Rose Interview, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Gaby Rogers Interview, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Barbaralee Diamonstein Interview, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Barbara Rose Interview, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Helen Weinberg Interview, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Richard Howard Interview, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Ellen G. Landau Interview, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Barbara Novak Interview, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1965-1981; 2.4
    This subseries includes draft essays, many with annotations, about Lee Krasner and her artwork. Items are arranged chronologically.
    - Ellen G. Landau, untitled manuscript, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)